miracletutorials.com 2018-12-21

# Privacy Policy | Miracle Tutorials

### Effective as from 14 June 2018

## 1\. Who we are

Miracle Tutorials is a project of Footprint Communication, registered in Belgium under VAT number BE0842326719.  
(“ **Miracle Tutorials** ”, “ **we** ” or “ **us** ”) wishes to bring you the best information available on video and audio. To be able to do this, and to offer you information and products described on Miracle Tutorials at [http://www.miracletutorials.com/](http://www.spotify.com/uk/) we use a content management system which automatically sets cookies. Some third party add banners may set cookies as well. This policy (the “ **Privacy Policy** ”) describes what personal information we may collect from you and what we will and will not do with that information.

## 2\. Sharing information with others

Unless you give us your explicit approval we will only share your personal information, including with Miracle Tutorials affiliates (being other companies controlled by or under common control with us) where there is a legal obligation to do so, namely:

  1. Comply with laws and regulations, requests from a governmental or administrative body or court, or to respond to litigation.
  2. Allow for a change of ownership of Miracle Tutorials (including but not limited to an acquisition by or merger with another company) and related transfer of all personal information to the new owner in which case any information remains protected in accordance with this Miracle Tutorials Privacy Policy.
  3. Allow us to use a third party to perform surveys measuring your experiences and use of our services (not permitting the third party to use your personal information for any other purpose).
  4. Allow us to share aggregated statistics about the use of our site and with our business partners.

## 3\. What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Newsletter

For our newsletter system, we use a professional service that encrypts transmissions to limit access to the system that stores your personal information when you subscribe to our newsletter. This service is verified by the [EU-U.S. PRIVACY SHIELD FRAMEWORK](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TNN8AAO).  
**You are not obliged to use your real name** when you subscribe and we actually encourage you to use a non existing name but the e-mail address must be real otherwise, you won’t receive the newsletter.  
All subscribers are asked to verify their subscription via e-mail. Only after you verified, you can receive the newsletter.  
**Important:** The newsletter only shows link(s) to the latest article(s) and its frequency is irregular. We only write if we have something worthwhile to say, which means that there will be long and short gaps between newsletter editions.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.  
An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.  
**You are not obliged to use your real name** when comment and we actually encourage you to use a non existing name.

## 4\. Unsubscribing from the newsletter

You can request to be removed from the newsletter database at any time at the bottom of the newsletter. This will take immediate effect. If for some reason you are unable to do so, you can [contact us here](mailto:subscribe@miracletutorials.com) to have you unsubscribed manually.

## 5\. How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

## 6\. What rights you have over your data

**Comments**  
If you have left comments , you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. We use a double opt-in procedure to make sure nobody else tries to impersonate you. We expect you to use the same e-mail address we have on record. We usually respond within 48 hours, except in weekends or official holidays.

**Newsletter**  
If you subscribed to the newsletter, you can request to receive proof that you are subscribed and what the newsletter system holds about you. We use a double opt-in procedure to make sure nobody else tries to impersonate you. We expect you to use the same e-mail address we have on record.

**Erasing personal data**  
You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes. For example, when you are blocked from the website for security reasons, we won’t give you information on that subject to protect our system.

## 7\. Where we send your data

Visitor comments are checked through an automated spam detection service.

## 8\. How we protect your data

We have a firewall which blocks illegal intrusions and we regularly update the website software. However, nothing is 100% secure on the Internet, therefore we cannot guarantee total safety at all times.

## 9. Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

You can set your device’s preferences to accept all cookies, notify you when a cookie is issued, or not receive cookies at all. Each browser is different, so please check the “Help” menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences if a browser is not listed here:  
[Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/products/firefox/protect-your-privacy/cookies) – [Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&hl=en) – [Internet explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies)  
Alternatively, you may wish to visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) which contains comprehensive information on how to do this for a wide variety of browsers.

### Third party cookies on our pages

Please note that during your visits to our website you may notice some cookies which are unrelated to us. When you visit a page with content embedded from, for example, YouTube, JW Player, Vimeo, you may be presented with cookies from these websites. We do not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the third party websites for more information about these.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, audios, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.  
These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

We use cookies for 4 purposes:

Cookie Type | Purpose  
---|---  
Session cookies | These cookies st by the CMS are necessary to allow us to operate the Miracle Tutorials Website as you have requested. They are deleted when you close the browser.  
Performance | These cookies are used by us or our business partners to analyze how the Miracle Tutorials Website is used. The cookies also let us monitor how the Miracle Tutorials Website performs. These cookies do not let us identify users. We use this information to maintain, operate and improve the information on this site.  
We use Google Analytics, configured with [anonymous IP addresses](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2763052?hl=en&ref_topic=2919631) to guarantee that you remain anonymous as a visitor. Web traffic reports are destroyed after 14 months.  
Functional | These cookies let us operate certain functions of the Miracle Tutorials Website in line with the choices you make. For instance,  when you write a comment and it is approved by us for publishing, the next time your comment will be published automatically.  
Targeting/advertising | Advertising on this site happens via affiliate links to other websites. These external websites may set cookies. We have no control over them, therefore check their privacy policies to get more insight. That said,  even if we let our business partners place the cookies for advertising we do not identify you to those business partners.  
  
As above, our business partners may use their cookies on the Miracle Tutorials Website. This is done to provide us with information about how the Miracle Tutorials Website is used.  
More information is available on the targeting of advertising and how to stop the use of these cookies. Please see [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) if you are located in Europe or <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/> if in the United States.

## 10\. Links

We may display links to third party websites. Please note that we cannot control and cannot be held responsible for the privacy policies of such websites. You should always read the privacy policy of a website to find out more about how personal information is collected and processed.

## 11\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

Miracle Tutorials reserves the right to make changes to this Miracle Tutorials Privacy Policy. If we make any material changes to this policy we will notify you by posting the new version of the policy on the Miracle Tutorials Website. It is your own responsibility to check the website for such postings from time to time.  
Your continued use of the Miracle Tutorials Website following the posting of changes to this Miracle Tutorials Privacy Policy will constitute an acceptance of such changes.

If you have any concerns, questions or thoughts on how we can improve our privacy policy, you can [contact us here](mailto:subscribe@miracletutorials.com).
